{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "fa1": "../../../AV/VisFormalLang/NFA/AutomataFiles/NFA2DFA2a.jff",
      "q1": {
        "type": "select",
        "src": "../../../AV/Development/formal_language/FAEditor.html",
        "description": "Start with the alphabet set. We normally represent an alphabet set with $\\Sigma$. The alphabet set is a set of symbols (typically letters or characters, but it could include any symbols}.",
        "question": "Which of the following are  alphabet sets?",
        "answer": ["$\\{a, b, c\\}$", "$\\{0, 1\\}$", "$\\{?, a, x\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{a, b, c\\}$", "$\\{0, 1\\}$", "$A$", "$\\{?, a, x\\}$"]
      },
      "q111":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "[T/F] c) $A$ is not the answer because it is just a character",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": ["True", "False"]
      },
      "q2": {
        "type": "select",
        "src": "../../../AV/Development/formal_language/FAEditor.html",
        "description": "Given some alphabet set $\\Sigma$, a string is a finite sequence of symbols (taken from $\\Sigma$, of course). Suppose we have $\\Sigma = {a, b}$, which of the following are valid strings?",
        "question": "Suppose we have $\\Sigma$ = $\\{a, b\\}$, which of the following are valid strings?",
        "answer": ["$babababbaba$", "$a$"],
        "choices": ["$babababbaba$", "$a$", "$\\{aaa, bbb\\}$", "$bacbabcba$"]
      },
      "q2_2": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Given some alphabet set $\\Sigma$, a string is a finite sequence of symbols (taken from $\\Sigma$, of course). Suppose we have $\\Sigma = {a, b}$, which of the following are valid strings?",
        "question": "[T/F] Choice $\\{aaa, bbb\\}$ is not the answer because it is a set",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": ["True", "False"]
      },
      "q2_3": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Given some alphabet set $\\Sigma$, a string is a finite sequence of symbols (taken from $\\Sigma$, of course). Suppose we have $\\Sigma = {a, b}$, which of the following are valid strings?",
        "question": "[T/F] Choice $bacbabcba$ is not the answer because it uses symbols in $\\Sigma$",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": ["True", "False"]
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "What states can be combined?",
        "answer": [
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,...\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$a,b,c\\}$ $L=\\{ab,ac,cabb\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{set\\ of\\ all\\ even\\ numbers\\}$"
        ],
        "choices": [
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,...\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$a,b,c\\}$ $L=\\{ab,ac,cabb\\}$",
          "$\\Sigma$={$0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8, 9\\}$ $L=\\{set\\ of\\ all\\ even\\ numbers\\}$"
        ]
      },
      "q3_2": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Is this one a langue?  $\\Sigma$=${a,b,c}$ $L = ab$",
        "answer": "No",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q3_3": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Is this one a langue?  $\\Sigma$=$\\{a,b,c\\}$ $L = \\{a\\}$",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q3_4": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "A language is simply a collection of strings defined over $\\Sigma$.",
        "question": "Is this one a langue?  $\\Sigma$=$\\{a,b,c\\}$ $L$ = $\\{\\}$",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q3_5": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Good, since a language is just a set of strings, the empty set is a perfectly good language.",
        "question": "Oh, and remember that we have a special symbol for “empty” set. Which is it?",
        "answer": "$\\{\\}$",
        "choices": ["$\\Sigma$", "$E$", "$\\{\\}$"]
      },
      "q4": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Another definition of a language is a subset of the powerset of $\\Sigma$. Remember from Discrete Math class that a power set of any set is the set of all possible subsets from the given set.",
        "question": "List the power set of $\\{a, b\\}$",
        "answer": ["$\\{\\}$", "$\\{a\\}$", "$\\{b\\}$", "$\\{ab\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{\\}$", "$\\{a\\}$", "$\\{b\\}$", "$\\{ab\\}$", "$a$", "$b$", "$ab$"]
      },
      "q5": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Useful notations: We usually use these symbols in our book, For symbols in some alphabet $\\Sigma$, we typically use either digits or letters near the start of the common English alphabet: $a,b,c,d,0,1$ For string names (that is, some variable that is meant to refer to a string), we usually use letters near the end of the common English alphabet: $u,v,w,x,y,z$",
        "question": "So, when you see $b$ in a sentence, it probably refers to:",
        "answer": "The character ‘$b$’.",
        "choices": ["The character ‘$b$’.", "Some string named ‘$b$’."]
      },
      "q5_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Useful notations: We usually use these symbols in our book, For symbols in some alphabet $\\Sigma$, we typically use either digits or letters near the start of the common English alphabet: $a,b,c,d,0,1$ For string names (that is, some variable that is meant to refer to a string), we usually use letters near the end of the common English alphabet: $u,v,w,x,y,z$",
        "question": "And if you see w in a sentence, it probably refers to ",
        "answer": "Some string given the name ‘$w$’",
        "choices": ["The character ‘$w$’", "Some string given the name ‘$w$’"]
      },
      "q6": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "There are some basic string operations we will use a lot. The size of a string is the number of symbols in the string.  We use the operator $|$$|$ to donate the size of the string.",
        "question": "Let $w=abbc$, $v=ab$, What is $|w|$ + $|v|$",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": ["6", "7", "8"]
      },
      "q7": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Another important operation is string concatenation. The concatenation of two strings $u$, and v is just the string that contains the symbols of $u$ followed by the symbols of $v$. We use the symbol ∘ to represent concatenation: Example : Let $w$=$a1a2...an$, and $v$=$b1b2...bn$ Then, $w∘v$  = $a1a2...anb1b2...bm$",
        "question": "Let $w = abc$, $v = 012$, What is $w∘v$?",
        "answer": "abc012",
        "choices": ["abc012", "012abc", "012", "abc"]
      },
      "q7_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "In reality, we use concatenation so much that we hardly ever want to be that formal. When we mean w∘v, we will normally simply write $wv$ instead.",
        "question": "Let $w = abc$, $v = 012$, What is $wv$?",
        "answer": "$abc012$",
        "choices": ["$abc012$", "$012abc$", "$abc$", "$012$"]
      },
      "q8": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Another form of string concatenation is to concatenate a string with itself. Suppose we have a string $v$.  The notation $v3$ means concatenate $v$ with itself 3 times. Concatenating a string with itself zero times yields the empty string $\\lambda$",
        "question": "let $v = ab$, what is $v^3$ ?",
        "answer": ["$vvv$", "$v∘v∘v$", "$ababab$"],
        "choices": ["$vvv$", "$v∘v∘v$", "$ababab$"]
      },
      "q8_1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Recall, since a language is just a subset of all possible strings, that the empty set of strings is a language: $L$ = {} = &lt;empty set symbol&gt;.",
        "question": "Is this a language? $\\{\\lambda\\}$",
        "answer": "yes",
        "choices": ["yes", "no"]
      },
      "q9": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Concatenating any string with $\\lambda$  gives the same string. In other words, $\\lambda$ is the concatenation identity. For example, $ab$∘$\\lambda$=$\\lambda$∘$ab$=$ab$",
        "question": "What is $\\lambda∘acb∘\\lambda$?",
        "answer": "$acb$",
        "choices": ["$abc$","$acb$", "$bca$", "$bac$", "$cba$"]
      },
      "q10": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Another useful operation is to reverse a string: Reversing a string means to flip it, in other words, write its symbols in reverse order.",
        "question": "Let $w = abbc$, what is $w^R$?",
        "answer": "$cbba$",
        "choices": ["$abbc$", "$bcab$","$cbba$", "$abcb$", "$cbab$"]
      },
      "q11": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "question": "let $w=abbc$, and $v=ab$. What is $|vv^Rw|$",
        "answer": "$8$",
        "choices": ["$8$", "$16$", "$24$", "$32$", "$40$"]
      },
      "q12": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "One of the most important operations that we use is the * operator, also called the closure operator. “*” of something means concatenating that something zero or more times. For example, if we have $\\Sigma$ = {a,b}, $\\Sigma$* means the set of strings obtained by concatenating 0 or more symbols from $\\Sigma$. ",
        "question": "Which of the following are strings in $\\Sigma^∗$?",
        "answer": ["$\\lambda$", "$a$", "$b$", "$aa$", "$abbabb$"],
        "choices": ["$\\lambda$", "$a$", "$b$", "$aa$", "$abbabb$", "$aaabababcc$"]
      },
      "q12_1": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "One of the most important operations that we use is the * operator, also called the closure operator. “*” of something means concatenating that something zero or more times. For example, if we have $\\Sigma$ = {a,b}, $\\Sigma$* means the set of strings obtained by concatenating 0 or more symbols from $\\Sigma$. ",
        "question": "Which are examples of $w^*$ where $w = abc$?",
        "answer": ["$Λ$", "$abc$", "$abcabc$"],
        "choices": ["$Λ$", "$abc$", "$abcabc$", "$aabbcc$"]
      },
      "q13": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Slightly different from the * operator, sometimes we want to have at least one copy of the thing that we are concatenating. Then we use +. One way of thinking of this: $\\Sigma$+=$\\Sigma$∗−{$\\lambda$}",
        "question": "Let  $\\lambda$ = {$a,b$}, Which of the following are strings in ?",
        "answer": ["$a$", "$b$", "$aa$", "$abbabb$"],
        "choices": [
          "$\\lambda$",
          "$a$",
          "$b$",
          "$aa$",
          "$abbabb$",
          "$aaabababcc$"
        ]
      },
      "q14": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Sets. As we see, Languages are sets, so all sets of operations can be applied to them.",
        "question": " Let $\\sigma$={$a$,$b$,$c$}, $L1$={$ab$,$bc$,$aba$}, $L2$={$c$,$bc$,$bcc$}, which element is included in $L1∪L2$ ?",
        "answer": ["ab" ,"bc","aba","c","bcc"],
        "choices": ["ab", "bc", "aba","c", "bcc", "a", "bca", "cb"]
      },
      "q15": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets. As we see, Languages are sets, so all sets of operations can be applied to them.",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$={$a$,$b$,$c$}, $L1$={$ab$,$bc$,$aba$}, $L2$={$c$,$bc$,$bcc$}, What is $L1∩L2$ ?",
        "answer": "$bc$",
        "choices": ["$bc$", "$aba$", "$ab$", "$c$", "$bcc$"]
      },
      "q16": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "In languages, $\\Sigma$^∗  represents the Universe set $U4$. Forexample, the complement of $L1$ will be the set of all strings in $\\Sigma$  except the strings in $L$. In other words,",
        "question": "What is ?",
        "answer": [" "],
        "choices": [" "]
      },
      "q17": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating two sets $L1$, and $L2$ means concatenating every string in $L1$ with each string in $L2$.",
        "question": "What states can be combined?",
        "answer": "{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bcbc,bcbcc,abac,ababc,ababcc}",
        "choices": ["{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bcbc,bcbcc,abac,ababc,ababcc}", "{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bcbc,bcbcc,abac,ababc,abab}", "{abc,abbc,abbcc,bcc,bbcc,bcbcc,abac,abab,ababcc}"]
      },
      "q18": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating a set zero times will give the set of the empty string $\\lambda$.",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$={$a$,$b$}, $L1$={$ab$,$aba$}, What is $L0$?",
        "answer": ["$\\{\\lambda\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{\\lambda\\}$", "$\\{\\}$&lt;Empty set&gt;", "$\\lambda$"]
      },
      "q19": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating a set n times means concatenating every string in L with each string in $L$ n times",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$={$a$,$b$}, $L1$={$ab$,$aba$}, What is $L2$? ",
        "answer": "{abab, ababa, abaab, abaaba}",
        "choices": ["{abab, ababa, abaab, abaaba}"]
      },
      "q19_1": {
        "type": "textBox",
        "description": "Sets concatenation. Concatenating a set n times means concatenating every string in L with each string in $L$ n times",
        "question": "Let $\\Sigma$={$a$,$b$}, $L1$={$ab$,$aba$}, What is $L3$?",
        "answer": "{ababab, ababaab, abaabab, abaabaab, abababa, ababaaba, abaababa, abaabaaba}"
      }
    }
  }
}
